juliasalbum.com 2018-10-21

# Privacy Policy - Julia's Album

At JuliasAlbum.com the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by JuliasAlbum.com and how it is used.

## Log Files

Like many other Web sites, JuliasAlbum.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

JuliasAlbum.com does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

## DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on JuliasAlbum.com.  
Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to JuliasAlbum.com and other sites on the Internet.  
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on JuliasAlbum.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

JuliasAlbum.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. JuliasAlbum.com‘s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browser’s respective websites.

## Google Analytics

We have implemented Google Analytics features based on [Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en).  You can opt-out of the Google Analytics and its various Features using [currently available opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).   The data provided by Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting is used to develop the content of this site in accordance with our visitors’ interests.

We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behavior on this site. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how you got to this site (what website you came from, etc.), the amount of time you spend on this site, what pages you visit next on this site, what kind of computer you’re using, geographical information about the visitors, and other information.

This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of this site and is not tied to personally identifiable information. We do not collect or store your personal information (that is, your name or address) so this information cannot be used to identify who you are.

Occasionally, we will compile aggregate statistics about the number of visitors to this site, their demographics, geographical information, pageviews statistics. No personally identifying data is included in these types of reports.  You can opt-out of Google Analytics using this tool: [Google Analytics Opt-out Tool](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

## ADVERTISING

Some of our advertisers may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited. These third parties may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, the web pages visited, number of visits, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it in reference to recipe ratings

### Comments

When comment ratings are enabled we store the rating a user has given to a recipe along with the personal data WordPress core stores.

### Cookies

When user ratings are enabled we store a WPRM_User_Voted_%recipe% cookie (with %recipe% the ID of the recipe) that contains the rating this user has given to a particular recipe. This cookie is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

### IP Address

When user ratings are enabled we store the IP address upon voting. This is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

### Their own manually input information

With the Recipe Submission feature personal data can be collected, depending on the fields that were added to the form. This can include the user email and name. When using the reCAPTCHA feature you will be agreeing to their terms of use and privacy policy.

## How long we retain your data

Our cookies are stored for 30 days. User submitted data is stored indefinitely in the local database.

## Contact information

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below:

Email: inquiriesjulia { at } gmail { dot } com
